<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>return address overwrite on The Mess Of Nebula</title><link>http://evalevanto.github.io/tags/return-address-overwrite/</link><description>Recent content in return address overwrite on The Mess Of Nebula</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>© 2023 Eva Levanto</copyright><lastBuildDate>Sun, 18 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://evalevanto.github.io/tags/return-address-overwrite/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>AHCTF2021: NameCheck</title><link>http://evalevanto.github.io/posts/namecheck/</link><pubDate>Sun, 18 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://evalevanto.github.io/posts/namecheck/</guid><description>For the birds It has been a while since I have blogged. The importance of doing so has not been absent only outweighed by the inertia(that dread to begin). This is the start of an attempt to put more of my thoughts on e-paper. I also maintain a telegram space where I dump materials/resources I encounter as I go along.
Checksec [*] &amp;#39;/home/levanto/Documents/Return-To-ROP/ChasingFlags/AHCTF/finals/namecheck&amp;#39; Arch: i386-32-little RELRO: Partial RELRO Stack: No canary found NX: NX disabled PIE: No PIE (0x8048000) RWX: Has RWX segments .</description></item><item><title>MicroCorruption: Johannesburg</title><link>http://evalevanto.github.io/posts/microcorruption-jo/</link><pubDate>Tue, 01 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://evalevanto.github.io/posts/microcorruption-jo/</guid><description>At this point in the journey, you expect a manual to greet you:
The lock is attached to HSM-1 module. Passwords that are very long are rejected. Just how long is too long? The main function just calls login.
The prompt states the password range should be within 8 - 16 characters long. However, from the input parameters of the getsn function:
r14: Holds length of the input buffer; 0x3f(63) characters.</description></item><item><title>MicroCorruption: Montevideo</title><link>http://evalevanto.github.io/posts/microcorruption-monte/</link><pubDate>Tue, 01 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://evalevanto.github.io/posts/microcorruption-monte/</guid><description>You find a manual:
This lock is attached to HSM-2 module. This means, no unlock door function in the lock firmware. This reminds you of a while back in WhiteHorse. The code follows internal secure development process. mmh. The main function just calls login.
The prompt states for an input range of 8 - 16 characters. However, from the input to getsn function:
r14: this holds the length of the input buffer; 0x30(48) characters.</description></item><item><title>MicroCorruption: Whitehorse</title><link>http://evalevanto.github.io/posts/microcorruption-whitehorse/</link><pubDate>Tue, 01 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://evalevanto.github.io/posts/microcorruption-whitehorse/</guid><description>Slaps you with a manual:
This lock is attached to a HSM-2 module. Function to unlock door no longer in the lock firmware. The main function just calls login. You set a breakpoint at login and a quick test input of aaaaaaaaaaaaaaaa
The login function:
The prompt gives a range for input to be between 8 to 16 characters. However, the parameters for the getsn function: r14: Holds the length of the input buffer.</description></item></channel></rss>